<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Amin Rashidbeigi</title>
    <link>https://aminrb.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amin Rashidbeigi</description>
    <image>
      <title>Amin Rashidbeigi</title>
      <url>https://aminrb.me/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:28:01 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aminrb.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025 in Review</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/2025-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:28:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/2025-in-review/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I look back on 2025, sharing updates from my work, personal life, travel, projects, and plans for the year ahead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ways I Can Help</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/ways-i-can-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/ways-i-can-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I regularly hold &lt;strong&gt;consultation sessions&lt;/strong&gt; (mentorship, one-on-one coaching, or whatever you prefer to call it) with individuals and companies in two main areas: &lt;strong&gt;topic-focused consulting&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;career growth guidance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic-focused consulting&lt;/strong&gt; covers areas that I’m currently focused on and actively studying. You can check the list of these topics .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, if you need guidance on topics not listed, we can schedule &lt;strong&gt;career growth&lt;/strong&gt; sessions instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How It Works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can book a &lt;strong&gt;free 15-minute initial session&lt;/strong&gt; to discuss your needs and challenges. If I can provide value and guidance in your case, we’ll discuss the next steps, including the structure, number of sessions, scheduling, and potential costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Am the First Reviewer of My Own Pull Requests</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/first-pull-request-reviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 18:23:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/first-pull-request-reviewer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About ten years ago, I started my career as a backend intern at a small company. Back then, the main product our team was working on was a multilingual hotel management software. After spending some time watching tutorials and practicing, the tech lead decided I was ready to contribute to the main project, so I officially joined the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I completed my first task, I nervously sent my pull request to my manager. Before even opening it, he asked, &amp;ldquo;Did you review it yourself?&amp;rdquo; I was a bit surprised and said no. He told me to go review my own code first, fix any issues that you found, and then send it back to me. He also suggested that I do these reviews before committing my code and introduced me to  for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 in Review</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/2024-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:59:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/2024-in-review/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will review 2024 and give some career and life updates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run Llama 3 Locally</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/run-llama-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:45:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/run-llama-locally/</guid>
      <description>A step-by-step guide on how to run llama 3 locally or on an external machine to have a free and self-hosted LLM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When to Start Secret Rotation</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/secret-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:11:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/secret-rotation/</guid>
      <description>An overview of secret rotation, discussing when to implement it to reduce the risk of data leaks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expedition Diaries: A Project to Learn</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/expedition-diaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 22:48:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/expedition-diaries/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I started Expedition Diaries, a personal project to explore old travelogues while learning full-stack development. This post reflects on the journey, the challenges faced, and the lessons learned in backend, frontend, and infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Sorry&#34;, Is That Enough?</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/actions-after-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 14:17:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/actions-after-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>Making mistakes at work is inevitable. How we respond defines our personal growth and impacts others. This post explores different ways to act after mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts on The Clean Coder Book</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/the-clean-coder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:31:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/the-clean-coder/</guid>
      <description>This post shares my thoughts on &amp;#39;The Clean Coder&amp;#39; by Uncle Bob, focusing on topics that I found particularly interesting or debatable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vector Search: An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/vector-search-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 11:39:47 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/vector-search-introduction/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we explore the fundamentals of vector search, discussing how it operates and its applications across different data formats. You&amp;#39;ll discover the key components required to implement vector search and its potential to enhance search functionalities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Overdue Tasks</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/managing-overdue-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 09:31:56 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/managing-overdue-tasks/</guid>
      <description>This post provides insights into managing overdue tasks, exploring various strategies for effectively handling such situations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go Test Doubles by Example</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/go-test-double/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:37:31 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/go-test-double/</guid>
      <description>Test doubles serve as an alternative to real dependencies in testing. In this post, we&amp;#39;ll review all test doubles using a real-world Go example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Extra Work in Programming Teams</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/extra-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 10:32:09 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/extra-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I read an interesting article by Ben Northrop that can be found &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. In the article, Ben talks about the concept of &amp;lsquo;doing extra,&amp;rsquo; which is not the same as doing more. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re asked to implement two APIs and finish early, you can use the extra time to think about how to make the implementation more efficient, secure, or reduce the code length. That&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;doing extra.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improve Onboarding through the Magic of Storytelling</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/onboarding-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 01:44:04 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/onboarding-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you join a new team, you are usually bombarded with a lot of information. You need to familiarize yourself with the company&amp;rsquo;s culture, facilities, and colleagues. Initially, the onboarding process tends to be welcoming and hospitable. However, after a few days, you are expected to quickly learn about the products, services, and data in order to contribute effectively. It can be overwhelming to try to absorb and utilize all of this information, and eventually, the honeymoon phase ends, leaving you feeling stressed and concerned about your credibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Engineering Managers Can Avoid Technical Decay</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/engineering-managers-avoid-technical-decay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 19:48:11 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/engineering-managers-avoid-technical-decay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an engineering manager, it can be easy to feel a sense of distance from the team and concerns about technical decay over time. But there are solutions to this problem! In this article, I explore ways to improve low-level engineering skills, in order to reduce the gap between you and your team members and maintain effectiveness in leading a technical team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading a lot (mostly on how things work and why they were created), re-doing (for yourself) technical design reviews, and having side projects can help.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Side Projects</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/side-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 10:53:05 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/side-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here, you can find some of my side projects, which I had a great time building. Even though most of them are no longer alive, they greatly impacted my career, and I am really proud of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-expedition-diaries&#34;&gt;🌎 Expedition Diaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love traveling, particularly when it comes to learning about new cultures. Additionally, I have always been curious about the cultures of nations throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expedition Diaries aggregates all of this curiosity in one place, as it documents the journeys of explorers who have passed through lands throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 10:52:53 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;avatar.png&#34; alt=&#34;Amin Rashidbeigi&#39;s avatar&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi! I am Amin and I hold a B.S. in Computer Engineering and an M.S. in Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am a software engineer at  Tech Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can contact me via email at a.rashidbeigi at gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countries I Have Visited</title>
      <link>https://aminrb.me/visited-countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminrb.me/visited-countries/</guid>
      <description>Interactive map of countries visited by Amin Rashidbeigi</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
